okay
let me bring up the twitch chat on my
phone here
that's how i do the one one computer
setup well i got my laptop with me you
know
what's that drake line i've been living
out a suitcase
uh you have a suitcase y'all got a
backpack so we'll talk
i'm gonna see how well the stream goes
what so how do i
go to my channel my channel
live to organize the world's information
hopefully everyone recognizes uh
what that line is from
drinking salt water coffee
probably google that and figure out
where i am
all right we'll give people a minute to
show up it's going to get hot in here
we're going to turn on the air
conditioner
and it's unfortunate because the air
conditioner is loud
so you get a choice
between you know it being loud
or it being quiet
all right so does everyone recognize
where the line comes from
organize the world's information
what's up it's google's corporate
mission statement
uh no it's not an asmr i did a lot of
yelling last night so i
lost my voice a bit
um
my kitchen i guess my kitchen's behind
me
i'm in a new place you guys always stay
uh on the movement and i'm gonna promote
and this is actually the first
i search for how to drop out right
my first result is wikihow
tradeschools.net
this some seo blog
right eight ideas like like like it's
until we get down to this one i mean
this is the first one that i think is
written without an agenda and
actually let's go back and let's confirm
that i'm not i'm not talking out my ass
we're gonna uh
i'm gonna bring up some of these other
ones and you can tell um the difference
of the looks in the website so let's
click the top one
right so compare the look of this
website on the left
to the look of the website on the right
right
i don't want websites that look like the
one on the left i want websites that
look like the one on the right
almost look at this one yeah exactly
if a website has um
like tweet save i don't want it right
how is it then in the age of beautiful
artificial intelligence
google's top results are this trash
um now there's three hypotheses for this
that i come up with quickly i'm sure
there's more
uh one is this is what people actually
want um and i'm most inclined to believe
that that's true
because you know it just just that's
that's like occam's razor
it turns out people actually want things
full of like
spammy ads and up see i scroll down well
look there's a pop-up wow am i surprised
no you know what i'd be surprised if i
scrolled down on here and there was a
pop-up
i recommend using thetradeschools.net
because you can find the program that
you're interested in
nearby or online right um
so hypothesis number two
is that google is somehow uh
making money off of this somehow like
this website
is leading people back to google or
maximizing some metric that google cares
about
at the expense of its users
hypothesis three is that google cannot
tell the difference
right and like look at these two
um let's so we have cora
um cora is it's it's unbelievable
how korra does this i will never sign up
for a core account
never korra would keep me on their
website so much more
if they didn't do this crap but they
continue to and like
that's a question for cora um
hypothesis number one is that uh this is
actually what people want
right uh let's see this one
this is better slightly better
um this is the kind of person who maybe
today is like a digital nomad you know
digital nomadism is a ponzi scheme
uh with the guy who made nomad list at
the top
it's not what people want well so let's
talk about the definition of people
certainly not what i want and it's
probably not what you want fellow people
in chat
um so let's see this one
i can already tell by how long it's
taken to load it's going to be trash yup
total trash
let me get to a medium article a medium
for the most part actually medium itself
as a company is becoming more
they're trying to monetize your content
it's shocking
uh try swisscows.ch
instead
wait are you kidding me this is
supposedly a good website
and we have this at least
at least when i go to google.com what
are they showing for local businesses
they have one shill line for whatever
bullshit you know
i don't know how google chooses this but
for the most part
um like google is a good website
right google hasn't become well let's go
to uh one of google's competitors
oh my god really i'm hearing something
about fox news
be afraid i have to look at a picture of
donald trump like are you kidding me
if there's a picture of donald trump on
your website it should immediately be
seoed way down
um well but to be fair let's let's let's
give
this a try even though i can tell
already from their website did i put it
in quotes for google
i did put in quotes for google um
to wikihows and then the one i'm looking
for okay that's actually slightly better
but like
really uh uh an image ad
um
gotta install the internet explorer
toolbars
uh all right let's see duckduckgo
uh duckduckgo is the same as this so i
mean it's interesting by the way to note
the ones that are different on google
uh so
the wikihow
here's an interesting one
how come on here the top one for both of
them
is how to drop out of society and here i
don't even
see that result
interesting
um now my dna sequence is yeah so the
problem with ordering that is i need to
ship it to an address
and you know i'm a nomad so i'm sure
there's some good solution for getting
shit
actually i have an address now for a bit
so i can ship it here
google doesn't want you to drop out of
society like i think that's a little bit
too sinister
uh go incognito i this is a i don't
i don't have browser history
i i wipe the cash i wipe it for you guys
it's the same
um because we live in a society and they
don't want gamers to rise up
i mean like wikihow's not a good website
the new better private search
what makes a good website i mean
well let's talk about some things that
make a bad website right
it's pretty easy to talk about things
that make a bad website right
and a lot of it you can tell by like
what is the
i mean really what you want to get at is
what the intention of the creator of the
website is
okay if the intention of the creator of
the website is to straight up
monetize on you right now like
clear clearly the intention of
tradeschools.net
is to get you to click put your zip code
in here
and then shill you on you know
continuing education opportunities right
so that is probably trade schools.net's
business model so the intention of
creating that content is to feed the
business model
um showdown.aya
oh no this is isn't this like i can
search for like ports and stuff
i've used that um
one without javascript frameworks that's
a general correlation but we shouldn't
immediately rule out any website with
javascript right
what i really want to get at is what is
the intention of the creator of the
website
if the intention of the creator of the
website is to sell me something then
like if i'm being put if the web page is
just the first one in a funnel
and the only reason this this web page
was created was to increase the size of
their funnel
i'm out so we can we can rule that out
that's a bad website
um another example of a bad website so
this
it's it's less clear exactly what the
call to action is here
um well actually no we have the call to
action right here you you can tell
you can tell a lot about a website just
by looking at its call to action
so this guy is trying to get people to
sign up for his newsletter
uh and then through his newsletter he
probably monetizes in in some different
way
um oh here we go
i'm sure his teach yourself anything
bundle is free but you know
when you realize that anything doesn't
include the thing you want to learn
he'll sell you that bundle for just
um 3.99 a month
more uh i
don't have access to the gbt3 api
i didn't sign up for the beta and i
don't think openai likes me
for various different reasons
so i don't think they're going to give
me uh access to the beta
so how would someone continue to make
sites if they can't make money all
sites have to be written by someone with
a day job i mean no like you can look at
geohot.com right
you know here we go like i made a
website and like it's you know i joke
i chill for my instagram my rap career
uh little link to comment ai there but
like you can look at this website and
realize
maybe another like metric that you could
use and kind of like an adverse metric
is like how unique your website is
right every
good website like they look
different but they have a similar sort
of
maybe another thing that you could use
to judge this is how much
time was put into the content creation
right
um
you can access it through ai dungeon oh
cool
uh
how would you track this i mean so
there's a lot of ways today to do it
i could train a model on on uh
i could train like a comm net on on a
screen grab of the website
um but so part of this stream the point
is if you notice the name of the stream
is to organize the world's information
google has become terrible
uh and the the thing that really drove
me uh
over the edges i'm going to iceland um
i'm going to iceland in a month and at
the border in iceland you have to get a
chronovirus test
right um and i i typed the following
thing into google
does the border covid test
in iceland hurt all right i want to know
like what kind of
what kind of uh
like
this is different i think i phrased it
slightly differently last time
the first results are um
are uh icelandic so these are the top
two are government iceland
um and then it's
news right
iceland coronavirus test has its
skeptics but it may be working
right what i'm looking for when i type
that in is is i want an
anecdote i want an anecdote of
uh yo just cross the border in iceland
test hurt like a bitch
right um yeah so you always search
reddit so
let's see if we can do that site
reddit.com
uh
i mean that's interesting in and of
itself
does the border covid test iceland
nothing
in iceland yes it's like
you know you just wonder what their what
their algorithm is anymore
um so again this is people commenting on
a
news website news is a category
another thing that i'd like to do with a
search engine
is um another way you can tell that this
is a better website then then here we're
going to bring it up and we'll see it's
going to be bad
you can tell that this is a better
website than this
is this website has been up in a very
similar format
for 16 years
um and it has relevancy 16 years later
if something is still relevant on the
internet after 10 years
it's a good website this thing
is going to have a traffic profile that
looks like this
right and all news websites do i would
like a search engine that down waits
for relevant recency
um i'm telling you like like i was in i
was in clubhouse and we were we were
chatting and that's how this stream
started
and yeah the idea is kind of
i want someone to do this i look i
really i don't want to do this you know
i got i got i got things to do man
i've been hanging out i've been reading
articles about how to drop out
you know i'm a bum um but
for the world and i didn't realize by
the way how much superhuman charged
um i mean superhuman this is it's it's
a month right i would totally pay 30 a
month for a good search engine
actually i would pay a hundred dollars a
um it would easily give me 100 a month
of value there's tons of value to be
to be captured here and the thing about
a subscription model is your user
aligned
right the more value you provide to the
user the more you can charge the more
money you make
um
google is better google's better than
what the lindy effect what is the lindy
effect
[Music]
hmm
yeah the longer you wait the longer
you'll be expected to wait and people
think waymo is going to ship a
self-driving car
um open api based search what is what is
open api
uh i block twitter i've blocked twitter
on both my phone and my computer
fuck twitter it's it's a it's a terrible
website that
that promotes hate and controversy
um yeah one challenge at the internet
today it's grown on offering free
services by advertising selling data
instead of charging for the service yeah
and like i
think this is changing um
and i think that's okay
like i think this is probably going to
happen
um whether i do it or not so one of the
things that i wanted to look into on the
stream was
how hard is it actually to index the
internet
let's look for estimates of the size of
the internet
i mean it's interesting like size and
billions of web pages so
um there's that old ibm quote ibm
called five computers
um i think there is a world market for
about five computers
and this was ridiculed
uh after the rise of the the personal
computer this was ridiculed after
everybody had computers on every desk
but
in a way we're kind of back there right
we have the google computer
the facebook computer the amazon
computer the microsoft computer
um and there's like little computers
running on some of those computers who
does twitter
twitter aws azure
google cloud includes twitter use
um twitter's on google cloud maybe
who knows it's not a very reliable
website
google cloud
golden.com
okay so this whenever you see things
that look like this
understand that this has been tried 70
million times
it still exists in app stores and it's
called yahoo categories does yahoo
category still exist
i don't think so um this is a bad idea
uh
google destroyed this and and destroyed
it thoroughly
anytime you think you can break the
internet down into a finite set of
categories you're wrong
or covet 19 is a category now
um google index is 30 trillion pages
yeah i'm not sure what that means and
then also so that coronavirus test thing
that i'm looking for when i search for
that now let's see if anybody can find
it please link to it all right i'm
looking for
a a a first person anecdote
of somebody who took the border iceland
coronavirus test
about whether it hurt or not right now
this
probably exists on twitter uh
reddit or facebook and part of the
problem is
those companies are adversarial to
google so there's no good way
maybe not reddit facebook definitely is
and google and twitter have some kind of
partnership
um comments on gab
no uh if
if the alt tech companies want to be
successful they have to do it from a
place of political neutrality
um if you have an alt tech ceo coming
on uh news uh
news shows wearing a maga hat
you're doing it wrong right and now i'm
not saying by the way that you know the
person who
who sets up these sites can't be a trump
supporter but if they come on the news
wearing a maga hat all they're doing is
promoting
controversy right and the culture of a
company follows the culture of the
founder i don't want another social
media company
that provoke that promotes controversy
um political neutrality is easier said
than done look like with all of these
things it's not a
there's no absolute political neutrality
but it's something to strive toward
um
pure tube is pure tubes oh i didn't
check the andex let's check the index
maybe the russians got it right or maybe
they have some other crazy bias you know
it'd be very interesting to see if
yandex has something like totally else
uh nope same as the others for the most
part
uh except they don't have the wiki how
about dropping out of society
oh what is this nope spam
i gotta tell right away by the first
things that load
are facebook twitter and pinterest logos
i've heard good things about yandex's
image search and i won 20
in a bet my friend thought that he could
take a picture of me
with his cell phone upload it to yandex
image search and it
would return george hotz it did not
um we tried out duckduckgo the all
similar
right none of these websites are
indexing based on
really quality the the
something kind of shifted maybe there
used to be like
seo spam and then content and
the um
the binary went to more of a spectrum
um oh you gotta check bing you're right
i gotta check bing
um bing did an info box for
tradeschools.net
like i don't even it's different is it
possible to drop out of society
according to the neoclassical oh it's a
core
question again here's here's another
big content base it is it's
it's a very parasitic sort of model
where
these companies and i don't really know
i don't really know the legality of i
think by posting on their website you
still own the content but you're giving
the company a perpetual license to do
whatever they want with it and that's
how it works at comma
how do i measure quality when there's
huge incentive to game the algorithm
well
a few things about that one if we make
our search engine elite
and only for the one percent who are
willing to pay me 100 a month to use it
um it won't be gained it won't be gained
uh because those users are probably
savvy enough to not be good advertising
targets anyway right like nigerian
scammers misspell stuff on purpose
um you'd never pay me then enjoy the
shitty uh enjoy the shitty search
damn i sure this is this company would
make so much money
oh man if i cared about money now bc if
i cared about money i'd be as bad as the
next guy once i
did it um
what are my opinions on clearview ai
what is clearview ai dude i don't know
you only heard about this because of
stupid news
if the news is talking about it it's
dumb and i don't want to hear about it
um yeah
oh so the nigerian scammers you get
these uh
these these spam emails about like oh
i'm a nigerian prince locked up in
blah blah blah and you can get me out
for three dollars then i will share half
of
you know what you know this game um
what if news talks about me well then i
guess i'm an irrelevant
uh i think tick tock is a chinese spy
tool
i i don't really see evidence for that
is tick tock total trash
sure but you know
this huawei a spy tool i've seen no
evidence of that
um it seems to be business protectionist
bullshit
uh there was a george hodge threat on g
last night what'd they say which one's g
i'm not going to four channel on stream
um thank you for subscribing
uh discord is real spy too yeah everyone
thinks they're so safe and secure and
discord right
um
golden is getting good what is this
golden thing
oh this oh this is the one is this the
one with the categories
yeah you can't do categories
okay so i promised on this stream i know
you guys like when i code on the streams
so let's think about how
if i wanted to index the internet how
would i do it
um so i know there's this thing common
crawl that people are using to train
like the gpt's
um
cc index
300 amps
yes
uh all right this stream is
brought to you by recess
uh not really you know
i don't underst these companies totally
sponsor me i'd chill so hard for their
products
we canned a feeling not tired not
yo red bull actually did sponsor me once
uh they sent me
two cases of red bull and i shield hard
for red bull
uh hemp extract calms the mind
centers the body american ginseng good
to hear it's american
you know in case you're a nationalist
you can support this ginseng
l-theanine and lemon balm
only 30 calories yeah we're doing drugs
and antidote to modern times what a
marketing slogan
no you see the internet goes in waves
so now we're in a wave let's use my cpu
i'll twitch
um
ny post is that a picture of mark
zuckerberg
sorry i don't have chat on here
um oh i took covet iceland test arrival
oh someone did it
i took covid iceland test
arrival sitereddit.com
uh we have to spell stuff right
oh here we go
i still can't exactly find it
mildly
you said mildly uncomfortable let's
actually just add those words in
mildly uncomfortable
i can't spell anything here we go
our experiences with traveling to
iceland good ah
perfect
see i guess that actually is not
it's a somewhat hard question right
um and it's sad i i feel
reddit is really um you know
there's a big decline coming to reddit
uh i wish these users could migrate
somewhere that isn't
uh vote or
i like what the win people are doing um
but again if you start out with the
donald dot win you get a certain kind of
person
um i have nothing against the donald
duck win actually i think overall it's a
pretty constructive
uh community now just people who
genuinely love donald trump and you know
want to talk to each other about how
much they love trump and like
you know any community that looks like
that is generally a positive community
versus toxic communities that talk about
who they hate and so on and so forth
um but
unfortunately by doing that one first
like
i'm consumed uh there was this subreddit
i liked to consume
product uh and now they've moved to win
um yeah and like you get like this stuff
now
and there was some of this on consume
product beforehand
um but it has now they're coming for you
and your families like
it has the same kind of political energy
to it
which at least the consumed product that
i remember didn't it was mostly just
ripping on corporations for astroturfing
um
to be fair like they were banned from
the website and banning creates
radicalization so on and so forth
uh you described it as mildly
uncomfortable all right that's good to
know
um that's what your twitch streams are
for now
uh am i proficient in algorithms enough
to pass a fang interview
hell yeah
if put it this way if fang is asking
algorithms that i don't know they're
asking obscure bullshit questions that
don't correlate to anything
um could i pass the you know
how do you feel about collaboration
you're going to have to sit through 27
hours of implicit bias training
are you okay with this um that those
stuff that stuff might be a little
harder to pass but in terms of algorithm
skill
um
what do you guys
i want a general compute engine to
replace the concept of uh
of search engines right um
you'll bet me money to solve elite code
question in like 20 minutes
all right what what question
uh people who think reddit is all hive
mind have never sorted by controversial
all right let's try it let's go to
politics
politics is uh
here we go biden to offer money for
something all right so the top comment
when sorted by best is shit like this
pays for itself when you look at
long-term studies
uh maybe maybe that's true um and then
you get to you know you realize that
there is no way you should take this
person
in any sort of good faith in an argument
once you see that
um you know this is things like that's
total
that's total trash right so the fact
that that's the best comment
says something already like are you sure
best is not searching for controversial
um or is this site is like
is this reddit our conservative hate or
something
let's sort by controversial and see what
we find
this is this is this is in a way a
better comment
um but yeah i don't know like
this is more controversial than
this i don't know
maybe it's a bad
um isolated codex
let's see what they find controversial
i mean there's not enough comments to
really
now new york times is threatening to dox
tucker carlson
is that not his real name
hmm this stuff actually does kind of
feel like weed man
uh i don't know look i don't want to get
into that i don't want to get into trash
um okay indexing the internet
oh actually i do want to make one quick
comment um
i'm gonna try to make this comment
nicely but i did i saw it on uh
on my comments from last time and just
um i saw two people write it
uh basic variations of it um
and i would hope that in the future when
people write comments like this
i encourage everybody to link them to
what i'm about to say
[Music]
um
here we go um
i'm a new customer as of this week i've
been following you and the company for a
few months and i think your product is
great
that said however i've lost two people
because of the virus and i'm
disappointed you are
using your voice to discourage
mask wearing
i'm disappointed you're using your voice
to discourage mask wearing
no i'm trying to find the truth right
and
i don't know people who look at the
world in that sort of way
um i saw another one where
like someone thought that i wasn't
serious someone thought that i was
trolling about the masks someone who's
trolling doesn't go on to read four
papers and say hey i'm looking for an
open mind
um looking at it with an open mind right
um
secondly why are you sharing your
personal opinion on a company branded uh
outlet in the first place
to be fair i don't run comment i archive
uh the name is a little bit i would not
do this from
from a company branded uh outlet but see
who take this pandemic seriously
right like a scientific argument against
masks is somehow at odds with
taking the pandemic seriously
right when you're dismissing simple ways
of staying safe
you must take the concept of safety
seriously
or you're only hurting the brand and i
hope you reconsider the power you wield
i want to make clear to people like this
that
this argument is
i will never buy into it right don't
tell me how to use my voice
right don't tell me oh you should
make this political calculation before
you speak
i think that that is a big problem uh
you know
in in the world today i saw another one
that kind of looked like it too maybe
this one was even more
um that one had more to do about and the
company's position on masks is coming i
doesn't care coming i has no opinion
coming i has no political opinions like
any reasonable company should
um i do i'm a person
[Music]
it's funny that this gets upvotes also
don't get any ideas about being another
bill gates if you believe all this covid
bs your iq is negative 9
000.
no but i want to find i want to find
more of the comment where
where people talk about like there's
like you understand that this is an
inappropriate way to use your voice
um and anybody who talks like that
immediately should be cut out of the
conversation
right i don't want you as a follower i
don't want you to interact with
any of my stuff because you're a toxic
person
right
also by the way this is a this is a
immediate telltale
who capitalizes one word uh in the
middle of uh
of a lot of words no no no i'm not
cutting them out because
they i'm not telling them what to say
i'm just saying i have no interest in
interacting with them right like i don't
understand why they
why they comment and you know want to
say things like this
and of course you know it's it's one
person i don't know where did the other
comment go
um
ah if your job positions are still
getting a ton of morons applying
then i wonder why i respect your passion
for engineering but you say a lot of
things without putting much thought into
it
did you watch the video attracting a lot
of low iq
individuals in the progress all it takes
is one quick look at east asia to see
that masks
do work you say a lot of things without
putting much thought into it
i feel that you might know this but you
like to troll or enjoy being outspoken
but in the end you just damage your own
brand
let me tell you something i don't give a
fuck about my brand right
like i hate this it's this it's this
treadmill that people
are on and it makes them a completely
fake person
um they think that like they don't think
of themselves as a person anymore they
think of themselves as a brand
you know
um am i not a consequentialist
again you can justify a lot with
consequentialism that is
i don't think you can break ethics down
into that but
um but in the end you just damage your
own brand
good fuck my brand and fuck you
and that's how i feel all right cool
uh that's that's my rant about that
sorry that was a bit of a side check i
was reading the comments and i was just
thinking about that and then i should
told myself like
why do i read the comments you know um
fuck brands that's right and fuck people
who
think they're brands
okay
dude this shit kind of fucks you up man
legal you know you could purchase this
in new york
don't read the comments yeah i mean
that's the real truth of it
all right what kind of file is this
this tangent was sponsored by weed juice
instagram hey i'm an instagram
influencer man don't eat our instagram
influencers i'm trying to grow my brand
with key demographics like women uh you
know my instagram is 93
men uh you know this is terrible if
you're trying to use instagram's dating
app it's a great dating app but
you know
this rant is brought to you by we juice
no all though no we're getting
distracted
how do we index
the web
let's see how common crawl does it
and then from
can we crawl facebook right so here's
here's the thought about how to do it
you could build a browser plugin that
sends all of the people who are using
its browser traffic to some central
database now they might not be thrilled
about this right it seems pretty privacy
invasive but like
i don't know i mean like i don't think i
would
install that plug-in even if it was for
a better search engine
but if there was an interesting way to
do that kind of thing locally
right can you
i mean one way to do it would be it
stores
all of the websites you visit and then
it does something like anonymization
level 10 right like
only after 10 people have downloaded
that same website
that same thing like like basically how
you can set your anonymization level
right
like it saves all your websites and as
soon as you've hit
duplication across x number of users it
then contributes that to the database
and that's how anonymized you are
um
we're talking about the white hat
approach obviously everyone's got to be
cool with this except for existing scam
corporations
well the thing about saying fuck
facebook is like okay
let's do um let's look at alexa top
websites right
this is actually if we could see this
over time
um so google's not a content creation
website i'm sure this is mostly
consumption what is teammate oh t-mall
oh it's a shopping website
that's the third most popular website
oh yes definitely
for 300 yuan i can buy 301 that's like
50 bucks
a lot of asian shit wow wait this
website is actually more popular than
baidu
huh
uh baidu qq facebook wow look at that
largest daily time on site um
what's this soho.com
wow it really takes people a long time
to log into team all
huh
the seventh most popular website gave me
a bad gateway
whatever it is i hate it there's a
picture of donald trump on it
what is this
it looks like yahoo this is chinese
yahoo
can you tell the difference
oh great i didn't need to know about
kanye west's campaign rally
did not need to know about that
um how about yahoo still sneaks in there
is number 10.
um
i mean what if this is even worth
indexing
like maybe there is there's there's a
saying that i've heard i think i've said
it a bunch of times on streams which is
google didn't index the internet google
became the internet
um it's unclear what an open source
search engine means
like with all these things look com is
open source but the models
uh are binary blobs right and the thing
to produce the model is not even even if
we did open source it
you need a super computer to run it and
this would be the exact same thing so
you could open source the search engine
but whatever your indexer is going to
be it requires you know super computers
with large amounts of bandwidth
um 15 managed to be team all again
i don't know about this team all
can anyone confirm this is actually a
really used website
and they're not just somehow scamming
the thing
it's a very popular site
isn't it bad for people to know the
search engines algorithm well ideally
you want to build
a search engine where this isn't true
right the dream search engine
i feel like we were getting there in
like 2015. i feel like it was actually
like impossible to game google the only
way to game google was to create a
quality website
you use every day do you buy things on
tmall every day
or is it for something else
i mean it's true that there's a lot of
chinese people but like baidu
is ranked underneath teemo right so if
you compare the u.s equivalents amazon
is 12th
and google is one that's a little unfair
though because google is more worldwide
but does this rank no this ranks the
other google separately
maybe not all the googles separately
because the only other one i see on here
is
hong kong
now here's india kodalyan is india right
it's an ecom in china so like e-commerce
it's chinese amazon
e-commerce online marketing
um in canada people still use google.com
instead of ca i say
it chatterbaits45 i mean how long before
we get to porn
well manga cams
i've never even heard of that one this
chatterbait is like my free cam's on
here
did that ever make it to the top reddit
is 18th
some people still have internet explorer
as their default browser
what's okiezone
indonesian
i feel like if all the languages i could
learn to speak this one like
their words are very understandable i
really like indonesian as a language
um
twitch doesn't like porn i didn't show
any porn
talking about chatter bait's not okay in
a scientific
understanding of the website you know my
thoughts on this boys like
um i'm gonna be me
and if i get banned i get banned you
know
i don't not say racist shit because i'm
afraid of getting banned i don't say
racist shit because racist shit is dumb
right but if if if they ban you
for like showing off how much money
you're making on twitch or for
discussing intellectually chatter bait
you know ban me i have objective
standards man
um
why did dr disrespect get banned that's
the real question can you not talk about
that on twitch
uh
now where are we going if we get banned
i mean you know if the internet doesn't
want me the internet doesn't want me
uh
apparently he himself doesn't know i
don't know the rumors about that are
wild
um okay one of these websites is worth
indexing
right do we ever want to link to a tmall
page
i mean maybe in a way search engine
means two things
right there's this search engine which
is just
like i know the exact website i'm
looking for
buy coffee maker i expect a link to
amazon
yeah perfect that's the exact link i
wanted
right now buy that coffee maker done
three clicks so for that google's very
good
um for the coronavirus testing they're
less good and then
i don't know does anyone have a search
query that we can like try
and think about like is the other kind
of search engine real
is the i want to know about something
well like this one right
actually that's not bad that's not bad
the top result there is
is in general who i would trust right
best wrestler ever
google is awful for scientific papers
yeah a consequence of study of the
regulation
and behavior of web crawlers
sort that table by the number of pages
that link to it
uh
login i can't get over t-mall you know
all right so most linked to websites
i mean okay this isn't interesting it's
linking to yahoo
and who's linking to microsoft
these don't make sense
people linking to bunga camps
i'm checking out bonga cams
um no it's not if you're incognito
i don't have a vpn handy but um
in here
yeah there's no point in doing this um
linking to amazon makes you money i mean
that's definitely true so how many
would love to ask that question how many
of those are affiliate links right
but really what on here is worth
indexing and then how big is this power
law let's graph this
i cannot get over teemo only 84 websites
linked to it is that what they're saying
or is this denominated in
i don't know
yeah so it looks like typical power law
behavior
like
uh the top five have um
10 million and then the bottom have
yeah uh four million although the the
top
10 of websites have 66 percent of the
wealth
um alexa data isn't great so is there
better
sorry your speaker is not connected
alexa
your speaker is not connected
i don't know there was an alexa here
hey alexa if you could turn yourself off
that would be appreciated
no no bros bros no like real talk i
gotta show you what the alexa is
this thing's creepy man
this thing was in the apartment
it's designed to look like a guitar amp
but there's an alexa hiding inside of it
yo i don't know i don't know boys
i know shit spying on me oh i guess it
wasn't because it wasn't connected to
the internet
um
no it wasn't on the wi-fi they messed
the wi-fi
that's a long story um yeah but once
there's 5g you're never going to be able
to disconnect
anymore you know
no it's not spying i unplugged it but if
things have 5g and a battery you could
never unplug them
uh shirts without stripes
what is that
hmm
yeah like the more i look at this
hmm okay
so well let's talk about what's not on
here there's actually not a single news
website on here
none of the news websites oh twitchy
none of the news websites individually
command enough clout to uh to make the
top 50 websites
so no no one goes to google news maybe
that's
maybe this is the wrong way to think
about it
like there's content in those silos
it makes me think the thing you want to
build isn't a search engine
but is a plug-in it's a browser plug-in
and what you want to do with this
browser plugin
is
i don't know how many people would do it
oh who who right now
if i made a browser plugin that uploads
all your browsing results to me
you can turn it on and off you can click
you can see what you've uploaded
uh who would use it
yeah it'd be open source
so what if it stored the stuff uh
what if it stored stuff locally and the
whole plugin is open source
you guys can see the plugin what if it
stored stuff locally
and then only uploaded things
anonymously if more than 10 people
have viewed them
well yeah okay i mean it's open source
you can you can audit the code i'm not
trying i'm not trying to scam i'm trying
to think about
could that be linked to you well hmm
okay well
wait what does it mean right like what
does anonymity mean at that point right
of course it would be anonymous it's not
gonna like you're not gonna have to sign
up with your name and a credit card or
anything
but the problem is like your unique
browsing history is a big unique
fingerprint to you by the way
i find it interesting that none of you
guys will do it yet google's already
doing this
you know you're uploading your entire
browsing history to google
right i mean i have a visceral dislike
for that as well but i accept that
google's already getting it
google's faces what i have a face i'm
gonna go i'm gonna go dock some random
people
um millions of people use google every
day but only 20 people will use yours
people really still think they need an
account with something to be tracked
nowadays yeah you don't google has all
your incognito results in with your
other results
um does chrome extensions even allow you
to
check browser history you know
chrome is open source
google is more opt out it's hard to opt
out of google it's very hard what
percentage page have google analytics
remove uploader ip clean up some
fingerprinting and i'll upload
i mean i think this would be the first
step i think this would actually be the
first step to building this kind of uh
search engine let's see if people are
doing it
um decentralized web indexing
i mean so what do you mean by encrypt it
right i can totally encrypt it while
it's being uploaded
of course i'll do that um
uh once it's on my servers i'm not gonna
store
do you really care if i do at rest
encryption right like
okay they have to crack the compute and
not just the data bucket but it doesn't
matter
um i'm looking for cirques so
i've used this uh
free meta search engine
each search result is live as a direct
link
i've used this before and my complaint
was that it was slow
oh no this isn't the one i used i used
um
i don't remember it all right i think i
tried to use this once
and
look at what the top result is
huh the top result is the website i was
looking for
the wikihows are this one's okay this is
better
this is the best search result quality
i've seen
uh i don't think it's gonna have too
much luck with the next one
um i like this thing
how does it work
so it's a meta search engine
um
so they're getting this from says nam
and duckduckgo
are you telling me like the thing on the
back end is making hits to these
websites
wow trash
i mean it could practically be a picture
of donald trump
i'm sure it's i'm sure it's the cz
donald trump
so it's it's this is really just says
now
this is another it's interesting that
this comes out
and comments on this yeah this is the
best one
um i found this website too i liked it
right you just tell it's better you can
tell this is a better website
uh this guy also has a her medics
podcast
which is pretty interesting um
says nam so that's all they were really
searching
yeah so this is just like i wonder why
the i guess it's because it's not
popular enough the other
search engines don't care
yeah i'm not that concerned about
tracking on the internet
um i'm concerned about websites wasting
my time
to learn a ranking function anonymously
collect train samples doing a lot of
research right
solid.mit.edu
tranco list dot eu
tranco list dot u
hmm let's see if team all's gone away
team all nope it's still here
windowsupdate.com
yeah power law that's powerful right
that's what i think of when i think of
power law
oh what is solid solid is an exciting
new
i feel like i've looked at this before
um
okay i mean just just let's do a quick
analysis on this site
what is solid solid is an exciting
new project
um
led by a thought leader
in a thought location
this product aims to radically change
right so let's let's just i'm doing some
critical analysis of the text here
um the way web applications work today
resulting in true data ownership as well
as improved privacy
um i was talking with my friend
and you know she's talking about how
there's a lot of change in the world
right now
the time for change is now and i'm like
what has changed me
um and yeah radically
change should scare everybody most
change is bad
i'm not saying change change is good but
most change is bad
right like like
think about think about uh you know
coming into someone's apartment right
and making a change
well you know you could make a change
you could knock someone's tv over right
it's a very easy change to make but
it's not a good change because now your
tv is on the floor right radical change
i knock everything over right that's
radical change
um i replace all of the furniture with
sour patch
kids right um yeah so
oh i don't like solid like anybody who
describes something like that trust me
they don't have anything real to say
um yeah this is trash
all right tell me what it really is
um let's see how we do on the same on
the same test
uh so okay we have we have a header
video
driven i mean here's a video of like
what it is right
and then here's the first text open
pilot open pilot is open source software
built that should link to the github
really
built to improve upon the existing
driver assistance systems and most new
cars on the road today
tesla autopilot like functionality for
your toyota honda and more
after reading text that let's see is it
the same length as the text
so that's 191 characters
and that's 251 characters after reading
those 251 characters
i have no idea what solid is i think you
should understand what openpilot is from
that
um how did you find your mission i'm
gonna show for that i'm gonna show for
that how to drop out website we can find
it on says nam
says nam
yeah google i used google to find says
name
yeah he made some point about that
about how like you know
if you're dropping out in order to find
motivation and meaning everybody who
does something
to find motivation and meaning is like
that's not how it works man nobody
who's good at anything or nobody who's
truly passionate about anything
sat down one day and was like how do i
find my passion i don't know google how
do i find my passion how
do i find my passion
oh yes perfect
lifehack.org jessica
dw let's see is this website gonna look
like how to drop out
no it's not no no
there's a banner the world needs leaders
with purpose and persistence
click here to join the free 30-day life
purpose
challenge oh
i see jessica hey there world changer
please please do my call to action
so i can send you spam email and you
know it's spam because they respect your
privacy
nobody who really respects your privacy
tells you that
um
all right uh i mean this falls under
this whole whole category of self-help
which is is
masturbatory trash um
should i pay jessica
all right is that water or vodka
straight vodka boys
i'm on my russia shit
um
oh no my phone's dying i missed your
resub geekin don't worry i got you thank
you for subscribing
um we're gonna play the obligatory music
during the stream
i mean this is interesting right just
their definition of the word search
engine
um search engines help to minimize the
time required
to find information the amount of
information which must be consulted
akin to other techniques for managing
information overload
i mean in a way this is the whole point
right there's a saying about
uh the difference between
american censorship and chinese
censorship
is when the chinese want to censor
something they
you know they censor it go google
tiananmen square in china and
you'll find your internet disconnected
for five minutes at least that's how it
used to be and you can't google it you
can buy to it
um in america what they do is present
you with just
so much misinformation that you have no
idea what to believe i mean
you know i grew up during the bush era
the war on terrorism right and it was
all it was all phony shit you know none
of it was true
um but they overloaded you and they just
told you all this stuff
uh you know it was hard to cut through
and now it's easier to cut through
because i think
maybe our ability to process information
has gone up but the information's gotten
more now the old things look quaint
um god
see can can we just can we just talk
like
trust me i do not want to click on laura
shins
forbes article 10 steps to conquering
information overload
um news
news uses the word passion in the title
save yourself seven ways to prevent
information overload
how much you want to bet they asked me
to subscribe to their newsletter
oh never mind nope i i they want me to
sign up for i'm sorry i was wrong they
want me to sign up for
projectmanager.com
uh they didn't they didn't newsletter
um if you want to find the dropout post
just search for how to drop out on my
new favorite search engine
says nam
um ted was right we need to go back to a
primitive society
i really enjoyed the unibar manifesto
growing up
um but like the communist manifesto it
gets
the problem's right he talks about
problems with industrial society
um he talks about problems with leftism
which very pressing to talk about in the
90s
uh pressing is not the right word there
sorry
uh before his time whatever that word is
um and then he talks about this form of
primitivism which is basically his
personal like just ideology right
uh which doesn't really have anything to
do with it's not a solution to the
previous problems
it's it's it comes off as as like
it's orthogonal the communist manifesto
is the same way the communist manifesto
introduces problems with industrial
society as well that actually look very
similar to the unibomber manifesto
and then says something about how all
private property should belong to the
state
which is a complete non-sequitur right
um at least you know the unibomber thing
is a little more clear to follow but
um he i think his arguments
there was a there was a well
this is the washington post
um
ah yes um this
this this point um
turned me off to the unabomber's hall
solution
to to industrial society would society
eventually develop again towards an
industrial technological form
he says maybe i think strongly but but
then his next thing is like but there's
no use in worrying about it since we
can't predict or control events 500 or a
thousand years in the future
the problems must be dealt with the
people who live at them at the time
i mean that's the ultimate cop-out right
it's it's kind of like
saying um you know
what should we do about uh ammo
here i have a concrete example about
this um
we have some people in the world uh i'm
not gonna uh
you know who think amazon is bad
amazon is destroying local businesses
right there's a movement against amazon
it's destroying local businesses shop
local
shut down amazon right these people
think that shutting down amazon is going
to do something
um and you could shut down amazon you
could actually technically do this you
you acquire enough guns and force you
can you could shut down amazon but
amazon will subtly pop up in many
different forms right they're not going
to be called
amazon you know but like you can you can
you can use your guns to stop
amazon as well but this centralization
of supply chains
and the centralization of of you know
that kind of stuff
you can't stop the idea right it's the
precursors that led to it
if you kill newton you don't stop
calculus leibniz invents it if you kill
newton and leibniz
you still get calculus right which is
let's see yeah i want to stop calculus
right so i'm going to get a time machine
and i'm going to kill newton and leibniz
when they're babies right
um would society eventually develop
calculus
maybe but there's no use in worrying
about it since we can't predict or
control the events now that luke newton
and
uh livenets are dead these problems must
be dealt with people with people who are
not me
all right team all maximalism
were you a team all maximalist
centralization is just part of society i
don't think that's true i don't think
that's true i think that there are
yin and yang causes and forces for
centralization and decentralization
um we're stressed
cantor well we'd never have
diagonalization we'd finally do away
finitism could finally be accepted in
mathematics we could all accept that the
integers and the reals really do have
the same cardinality and cantor let us
down a terrible path
for the last 120 years all right i'm all
on board as soon as someone gets a time
machine let's go i don't want to kill
him i just want to redirect him away
from math
you know what else did cantor want to do
with his life go to art school man
um
jessica's waiting to be indexed to my
new search engine
real numbers don't exist only naturals i
agree with this
i agree um well wait only naturals no
i'm not no i believe that only
computable numbers exist right
so like pi obviously exists because
there's a computer program that can
output pi
but the uh programs are can be put in a
one-to-one correspondence with integers
the number of programs in the world has
the same cardinality as integers so all
the real numbers that can be produced by
the programs are okay
the class of these is called computable
numbers these all exist
but uncomputable numbers do not exist
right and if uncomputable numbers do not
exist
the reals and the integers have the same
cardinality through the
tertiary thesis yeah man yeah where's my
math phd
what about infinitely long programs bro
infinity is not real right like things
can
trend toward infinity i'm not an ultra
finitist i'm not crazy right and by the
way these are all real ideas
um finite
dust finite
test um i love
i love what i end up i love when i meet
people who i end up in serious
conversations with fine autism about
no no no no some people take it too far
and um
they they they believe in ultra finitism
ultravionitism says there's actually a
largest number
now that is absurd um i mean there's
some
physical intuition for it right like if
you think about you know if the universe
is finite then
at least as far as writing a number down
obviously ultra finitism is true but as
like a hypothesis with which to
construct mathematics around it's
ridiculous
um right but if the universe is finite
you know you can only write down what's
the largest number you could write down
put another way what program could you
put in the universe that generates the
largest number and then
halts what's the busy beaver function
for the size of the universe right is
that
that's that's kind of what you'd want to
say right oh busy beaver five
yo i should go back to working on busy
be for five but that's uh i want to
solve
has anyone saw busy beaver five yet this
is this is a math problem that is
actually within
uh probably within my reach if i spent
months on
yes yes look it's still available it's
still available it's still a question
mark i could be the guy who gets rid of
that question mark
oh um
math stream well i have no idea how many
people are watching right now
wow 1231.
wow yo boys hit that subscribe button
you can do that just click edit no you
got to do it the right way you got to do
it the honorable way you know why
because you can click edit there but you
can't click edit
on my own personal wikipedia
right here this is my wikipedia
if you edit your they don't even have a
question mark they got a greater than or
equal to they're not even sure
this is on my personal wikipedia which
you can't edit
um sounds out of date oh yeah speaking
of
i don't know this get this gets a little
off topic but i think there's been some
on certain wikipedia articles here's an
interesting here's an interesting
thought experiment right um what if the
nazis had won world war two
right uh and there'd still be a
wikipedia um
and the the article about hydrogen would
probably still be true i think the nazi
conception of hydrogen
is very similar uh to the uh you know uh
whatever
this is whatever wikipedia is uh
whatever political affiliation it has is
probably they'd have a similar hydrogen
article but
if you wanted to visit that page about
things like you know
um poland or you know international
jewelry
you'll get very different uh results
probably things that are
much less true than the ones on our
wikipedia so the question to ask
is well the nazis didn't win the war
um we have this wikipedia but is it
truly neutral
where are the biases what articles are
biased well
it's a good question to to to ask um
yeah i mean what would what would
communist wikipedia look like right
maybe not so different from our work if
we're not gonna go there all right um
don't twitter about bias
a busy beaver articles bias let's say do
we do we see bias
no i don't see bias like like because
the busy beaver game consists of
designing a halting binary alphabet
turing machine
which writes the most ones on the tape
using only a limited set of states
one way to see if there's bias is look
for extra words
right like
there aren't really any extra words
there so where could you inject the bias
it's the shortest description
um
the history is written by the winners
right uh
they tried to use force as a starting
point well you can look up like
lysenko-ism if you want to look at like
weird russian uh
bad science
ah okay yo yeah you can come check out
my private wiki at
localhost
um colon 9454 which is
wiki spelled out on a thingy
um
yeah but you know what they say about
historians you know
well only the winning ones survived
sometimes sometimes the losing ones just
had just were cancelled
you know gotta cancel don't get them
publishing deals man
they are the wrong side of history
uh it says error connection refused yeah
that's because it's my private wikipedia
you see how my firewall is blocking you
from
um
there is someone actually driving all
closed
yo by the way for all people who are you
know think that i'm concerned about my
brand i encourage you
right now to go to your windows system32
folder
and delete all the files in there right
just do it man
do it just don't wear a mask you know
like some guy on twitch told you to man
delete all your files man go to your
bank account
and buy puts
for something that's put all your money
into puts
tomorrow on disney you know that's
illegal i don't think i can say that
can i say it if it's a joke can i give
jokes stock market advice
i'm buying opposite disney put so i'm
betting on people putting puts on
i don't know man all right
um yeah so
i think i mean we decided kind of what
we're writing it's gonna be a browser
plugin
um let's see what i can get chrome
plug-in they did some like crackdown
recently
um writing a chrome plugin
oh here we go how to write a chrome
extension in 15 minutes flat well look
yes shield for your books
terrible
um you guys notice i'm not running
chrome i'm running chromium
get a typescript chrome extension
boilerplate on github
oh then i got a code and type script
let's let's let's do this let's
it has no instruction include a
background
um let's go through this tutorial seems
kind of fun
uh
load unpacked
and instruction although the extension
has been installed it has no
instruction introduce a background
script by creating a file titled
background.js
or just downloading it here
the extension is now aware
that it will need information from a
persistent variable
as soon as it is to be installed
inside the uninstalled listener
what
um i apparently also need to give it
permissions
or storage
the color is green what
color is green
this one will be a pop-up
button id change color
[Music]
all right we got to turn the air
conditioner on hopefully it's not too
loud
loose but only because you're subscribed
do i have thoughts on gpt3
yes
you ask you guys for no question you get
a yes or no answer
that's hope it's not too loud at all so
loud boys it's so loud
so
you know what i just realized
why am i doing this at the chrome level
right
i know the thing we already want and it
already exists it's called obs
right how many people would live stream
their screen all the time
right
it's too loud it's too loud it's gotta
go
um
so one of the problems with live
streaming the screen
is that's less structured data right
is the data on the web i mean
part of the problem too would be
how do i deal with like web sockets
right
i mean increasing amount of stuff is web
sockets
yeah you'd have to ocr everything you
would
i'm surprised that was the first dropout
i had of this internet by the way
um
lots of normies in chat
lo-fi air conditioner
they realized i caught the alexa and i
caught my head on
um no we're not coding a project right
like
a lot of times i just sit and like i use
the tools of programming to think about
programming
right obviously if i was trying to build
a very concrete chrome extension to do
something
you've seen me like when you saw watch
the stream where i make voice app right
i made i had something very clear that i
wanted to do and i got it done in 30
minutes
the thing is i'm not exactly sure what i
want to build with the chrome extension
right
so i can build something that sniffs all
traffic um
but i don't even really need a chrome
extension
for this right like i could do this with
like or like
like a root kit kind of thing right i
could do this with just something that
sniffs all the internet traffic when
chrome does https
is that in the chrome process
i guess it has to be but it's linking to
stuff like live ssl
right so i mean the right thing to do
might actually be to do like an ld
preload like thing
right if i ld preload and i just
intercept all of the
uh all the calls to connect
right i do it at a syscall level no but
that's also not gonna i can't do it at a
cis call level because that's not going
to get me around https
all right and then the other problem
with that
is you kind of want both right
you kind of want both there's some
information that you get from the
picture
and there's some information that you
get from the uh from the text
i would actually say there's more
information you get from the picture the
live stream is better
yeah i don't want a chrome extension i
take it back
if you really wanted to build
if you really wanted to organize the
world's information
yeah schiffer
but for uh yo
like you guys remember schiffer from the
shifters it was a comma dash cam app
that like records all your driving
um and i'd always talk about life
shifter man life shifter is like it's
shifter but for your life you know
like imagine wearing google glasses and
you're always live streaming it's just
in tv right now these ideas are new
um
but yeah what if i just stream the
screen
shit while i'm at it why don't i stream
the camera too okay
here you go i'm the first user of the
product
um yeah dr disrespect did get a
three-day suspension or
two-week suspension for streaming in a
public bathroom right
no this would just be you kind of want a
phone version of it too right
and then actually the give back this
gets a little bit more sinister
but you could brand the whole thing as
like a
uh use your time better you know
do it as a partner
be the largest bandwidth using botnet
ever get shut down like that
right well my command my uh
my command and control server needs to
deal with a million concurrent video
streams
yeah man i think that's beyond the realm
of what the black market can do
downloading the entire internet with a
one gigabit connection only takes three
million
years would you get that stat
this is so sketchy you would be worse
than zuck
why do we not like zuck you cannot like
facebook you know
disrespect made a new song do i have to
google this no
we're we're we're brainstorming the new
google we're gonna
build a company with two principles
we're gonna organize the world's
information
and we're going to um
we're going to uh
don't be evil yeah we're going to not be
evil we're going to don't be evil
that's that's true and if we ever delete
don't be evil please
don't be evil is going to be our company
motto and if don't be evil
ever goes away it's a canary in the coal
mine right
so when did don't be evil go away from
google
um ah yes in october
2015 alphabet took do the right thing
uh as its motto
right so this is the
like you know people have warrant
canaries on their website
google had a canary under don't be evil
and before october 2015
uh google wasn't evil and that's the
date that they become evil and it's nice
they just tell you
um everyone in the company needs a dopey
evil tattoo i like this kind of thinking
uh being evil is the right thing no see
do the right thing is horrifying because
everybody thinks they're doing the right
thing
hitler thought he was doing the right
thing and stalin thought he was doing
the right thing
um but if you ask these people
are they evil they'll probably go on
some long
diatribe about how evilness is all
relative because you know they know in
the back of their heads
if you're disappearing people and you
know exterminating millions of people
you're evil and like you know that
everyone knows that everyone who's a
human knows that but
just because it's evil doesn't mean it's
not the right thing
um do the objectively right thing there
is no objectively right thing
rationality is a great tool once you
figure out
where you want to go it tells you how to
get there rationality does not tell you
where you want to go
and anybody who claims it does is a
quack trying to peddle religion is not
religion and there's a word for people
like that and it's called hypocrites
um let's do some math bro prove you're
not a noob
uh what math you want to do
do you restrict information to a subset
like text only i don't think so
yeah it is a problem right classic
um
wait where did the leak go i'm not
playing league code guys
we're we're we're thinking about this is
a thinking about the future stream
you know trust me my skills are just as
good as they were
uh when i did those other streams
evil is much easier to agree on then
identify than rightness yeah it's true
build an extension that builds a profile
of you based on your typing patterns i
mean yeah so really what you want to
build for this
is a is a botnet kind of thing it's not
a bucket but a root kit
right
and that's kind of the
yeah like like why am i restricting
myself to network streams right i want
keyboards as well i want microphones i
want
i want all the data um
but not really i don't want all the data
and i think the key to doing this in a
way that
people would consent to it involves
pre-processing the data heavily on their
machine
right because you know
no one has a problem with their data
being used in anonymous
ways to improve the service i mean like
a few people do but
the problem is if you're giving them
that data there's no guarantee that
they're not going to update the terms of
service tomorrow oh
these terms of service here's a contract
where i'm going to sell you a sour patch
kids for 2.99
please note that i can update this
contract at any time
and you have to agree to the new terms
and i'm like i'm kidding
the 299 we're removing the decimal point
now it's 299 dollars and now i'm sending
you a bill for 297 dollars
i hope you like those sour patch kids
even the disgusting orange ones
um no avx 512 is useless
uh root kit not a butt no
this is not a root kit um
fingerprints digital
i mean in some ways what i'm building it
looks kind of like screen time
right
it's not what you do it's the way you do
it
all right to be fair our slogan to comma
is make driving chill it's kind of
meaningless bullshit
join us in the future of security
that provides continuous authentication
okay that kind of means something with
privacy
friendly all right i'm gonna i'm gonna
rewrite
i'm gonna rewrite their their their
thingy right
um we provide
continuous
authentication using behavioral
biometrics right look at that
removing bias
wow and i can also replace that i can
replace that whole thing with that
i'm going to improve these people's
websites for them let's go let's improve
their website
that can go
i don't really like that they're
wrapping
maybe we'll put it in the h1 i gotta
make their website look nice right i
don't wanna i don't wanna deface their
website
um no no no
oh see this is why i'm not a designer uh
we need some honestly it's a better
website it's definitely a better website
already
i would like the rap to be a little bit
better
um maybe can i put a can i put a br in
here
is this this is actually going to put an
actual literal br yeah great
can i put a slash n
no it's a literal slash n that's great
can i put a width tag on the p with
equals 300 px
didn't listen to that for some reason
i don't know why
um
filter with
oh maybe i'll just put in a right border
on the left border and that'll fix it
i could probably just do that here
what can i is that not a property i have
to do style equals
man we're really going in the weeds here
boys
oh this p is like a span tag
who knows
never mind though the web is too hard
make the p
a block oh yeah good point good point um
what is it
uh style equals text
block or something
no display block right
oh yeah who's excited for my my css test
oh i'm failing man inline block
be an inline block oh that did something
oh now we're getting closer
oh you know what i miss i missed front
page man front page was the shit oh
beautiful
there we go yeah display blah
digital fingerprints yo improved your
website i'd love to submit a pull
request right now
um now
instead of the word privacy friendly
there may be some truth to that
but
let's figure out how their privacy
friendly works
um maybe i can say something like local
using um like if that's true i don't
know i don't want to lie for their
company
because it might not be on device but if
that's how they're doing it
oh man dude people should pay me for
this shit you know
um what is the stream it's where we make
fun of losers you know
um my
clubhouse profile i took there's a line
from oh it's a really nice song
um
uh yeah no really you know but i don't
mean it i don't mean it to demean people
right
uh i want everybody in the world to feel
the vibe of this
it's like i let this slide when we were
younger you know you don't have to write
like this
the whole world's full of losers if you
get a chance to win you should take it
i'm not doing type eraser i'm not going
to be put into a box with my slow hunt
and peck
typing score
um oh how much data is on the internet
well yeah but most of that data is
like you know poorly compressed porn
videos
[Laughter]
the kind of kind of trash i'm talking
about don't be evil
all right um
sorry i still don't know what that
company does
i don't think they do anything they yeah
they're a microsoft silver partner
that's good
uh oh i know these like basic ideas i
doubt it works very well
it's kind of like google uses this to
decide whether you get those terrible
captchas or not
robbie billions thank you for
subscribing
um
i'm blocking some sketch you know what
is there a plug-in chrome plug-in
kb of javascript on website
i mean that's a cute one right uh
all right i kind of like to know before
i click on any link
how many you know hundreds of kilobytes
of javascript there is on the website
i bet you this one's good i bet you this
one yeah see not terrible
right how many look how many panels it
has
one way to tell how bad uh
websites are based on how many panels
they have right like this one has has
if it has three panels it's probably not
great like i don't know if we really
count that as a panel
um no but this one doesn't have panels
panels aren't a good way to do it never
mind
i take back about panels
sometimes there's no way to know how
much will be downloaded yeah of course
it's racist theorem why is this human
boy's racist dude
um no we had like a couple sips of this
recess
and you know it's it's uh
stronger than you think
um you would love hey.com that's hey.com
oh yo all i saw from them
was like poorly disguised marketing
stuff
as real user you know you're not
louis the 15th isn't better than louis
xiv
i don't actually know i know some of the
louis sucked and some of the louise were
okay
um
thank you we need to plug into
minimize.js well i have a plug-in to
minimize js
it's called no script i'm going to show
you guys a real life hack right here
live on stream
so you know you click a bunch of new
york times articles
and then the new york times gets very
upset with you and it's like
thanks for reading the times create your
free account to log
in you just click this
and look now i have a website again it's
called no script it's
cheaper and better than a new york times
subscription
um check out unify id
um
yeah again what's their security model
it's patent pending technology it's junk
um how do you do that no script thingy
you download no script
um you like how you block does it oh the
other thing that we talked about briefly
in the clubhouse chat if anybody knows a
good one of these
um for example
so here i am on youtube right i don't
want this
up next i want to i want an ad blocker i
think you can do it with ad blocks
boom youtube's better
all right it's a little bad how like
that still comes off and how it's
wasting
uh our house just said um wasting a part
of the uh
screen but there we go i just improved
youtube you can do the same thing on
twitter
uh facebook you have to remove the whole
front page the entire news feed is trash
i mean newsfeed is when facebook became
uh bad
um if you ignore it being blank right
like i'd like
you know so like this is something i
could do if i put time into it
but then i have to maintain it ideally i
want someone else to maintain like i
wanted to exist but i don't want to
build it what's the business model i
don't care about money so on and so
forth right
um i don't have a facebook
um have i ever read mindset
by carol dweck
no i haven't let's say
uh
oh is this about growth mindset
let me tell you about growth mindset
sorry um
scott alexander apologizes every time
before he says it but then he says
growth mindset is bunk bullshit
um whether you think it doesn't matter
right um the key to getting better at
anything is working hard
it doesn't matter whether you not
working hard but like doing it a lot
right it doesn't matter whether you do
it a lot and think you're never going to
get better or do it a lot and think
you're going to get better it doesn't
matter
self-help what are they what are they
rebranding self-help as these days
oh graduate test guides
i don't know if that's a troll i don't
know if that's a troll
um you need to work hard at math uh
where's my where's my busy bee for five
work
now this i mean this has been my little
project what will so far for a second
um merge sorts in many languages i've
kind of been maintaining this
is this terribly written yeah that's
terrible
bro bro bro
so many lines i mean that's good but
like
refactor that bro too many lines uh it's
merge sort in all the languages
i did coding last stream and then i
didn't stream it but i wrote merge sort
and cock
and i wrote a proof that it terminates
um
i never met irish schwartz let's check
out his website
oh that's sad
and his cert expired
oh okay good it works on http
i wonder if we can fix that who's
running it i'd be happy to donate and
give them a serve
no i didn't really like his uh his
writings on infinite chest
and vagina some of my favorite books
uh yeah i've read a lot of these like a
lot of these bugles
only saw it right um
aggregate of the posts
uh the response was gibberish i think it
has to do with like the wrong
tls version or something i've seen that
before
um
all right king herring i don't care if
you're a subscriber no no
shilling for crap um
let's encrypt starts are what i've heard
from uh people work at comma
is we don't use them because like
they're with some sketchy providers that
are going to be blacklisted by browsers
or something so we just buy it so
uh you can see who's sir we bought
uh who's certified buy
we use cookies oh no we don't tell
people we use cookies oh wait
what we're actually using let's encrypt
never mind we use let's encrypt maybe
it's not bad
uh we don't talk about common eye here
but we're talking about https when i'm
talking about comma ai
right we can use com ai as an example
what do you think about tesla's opinion
i don't think about tesla's opinion
um no no one's getting fired i trust
that they did the research and probably
know better than i do
uh
oh yeah you read the dropout essay read
how to drop out
is it easier to get hired at comment no
um it's more standardized like we've
standardized the process
a lot more we have much more objective
metrics on our candidates
um you know we think that like bias and
discrimination
and hiring process is super dumb bad and
what's the best way to evaluate people
programming challenges because what's
common ai a big long programming
challenge
um bro i could have bought bitcoin at
like 10 cents and now it's like 10 grand
bro
that's like 100 000 x man
i could have turned the crack rock to
mountain
um oh any more life-changing essays
uh
yeah yeah you want a life-changing essay
i mean i don't know i don't know how
life-changing it is anymore but
this essay changed my life more than
anything um
this this this essay changed my life
more than anything
uh i ever read
but i read it when i was 15. like now
everyone knows it
meditations on malik is really nice as
well sorry to link
just google look on the page and google
something
like in quotes and you'll find it
google's not that bad
all right all right could have bought
stocks people no
um yeah but you know what do you get any
credit for knowing about it before it
was cool
no you should have monetized that shit
boys
um use secondary as a css selector in
blocker
see i wish i wish somebody else would um
you'd caskey fire alarm
am i giving up on the search engine all
right let's let's let's summarize our
takeaways and then that's kind of the
stream we're not going to index the
internet in the stream
it's unclear even what indexing the
internet would mean
right like
in some ways this problem has been
solved by aggregators
well let's see
is everyone on hacker news to say
past no
so this is not what i want what i want
to know is what were the top stories
ever on acro news but no that might not
really work
either my first thought here is like you
know in china they give everybody this
test
uh and then the students who score in
the top point one percent of it
like go to like chinguan university or
something like the top university there
um the problem is the top
taking from the randomly sampling from
the top five percent of test takers
is probably better at achieving almost
any desired outcome
than taking the top point one
because you get weird people who are
frequently good at tests and not much
else
um
you guys crashed yukowski's site how
many people are watching this right
wow 13 12.
wow people are interested in this stuff
it's interesting
um
all right i think this is most of
today's stream
no let's let's really try to come up
with a coherent summary of take away
what does it mean to organize the
world's information
um
oh wait i want to do this
oh never mind i don't wanna i don't
wanna train anybody for
government business insider trash no i'm
hungry i didn't eat any food today
all i had was that coffee i gotta go at
lunch
um i'm in new york city i love new york
city
go out get some new york city pizza
you know i got a date tonight
it's all good it's all good life's good
man
life is good how much is my college
gonna cost
so here's another thing about that um a
few things
uh admissions is uh just an iq test
um and everybody who has uh does uh 130
or better can
can come um and freshman year is free
uh so like here might hear my thoughts
uh yeah
above 130 on an iq test and freshman
year is free
and then at every like
after the semester you have your final
exams and
there's a hard cut off it's not
nothing's curved but there's a hard cut
off and everybody below the hard cut off
is
is kicked out um they fail and they're
kicked out
uh yeah and then for sophomore junior
and senior year
i'd like to charge what you could
comfortably make in a tech internship in
a summer
so something like 15 grand a year
students are not required to use vm no
and you know with respect to the sat
correlates with iq very well
yeah so yeah i mean i think that one of
the things we could do i mean i'd want
to make a research university and i'd
want to do a lot of research into
uh intelligence tests and what
intelligence is i'm very interested in
intelligence
um not just human intelligence but
machine intelligence all
kinds machine intelligence systemic
intelligence corporate intelligence
intelligence services um
this is another another startup idea
that we talk about sometimes is um
making a a private nsa
like uh as a parent here kind of but
what if we made like penalty for people
like what if you made a private
investigation company but like really
good
um 130
you could say 130 is low and we would
see i mean we'd see as this grows
we might have to introduce other uh
objective criteria
in the cutoff um let's let's google
something i don't want to say this if it
isn't true
um but how mit
uh rose to prominence
um
i don't know this is hard to find but
what i'll say is the the theory that
i've heard about mit's rise to
prominence
is a harvard discriminated in ways mit
did not
um and i think today's universities are
discriminating
uh like they discriminate based on i
mean now they're throwing the sat out
entirely
where the s.a.t you at least have some
objective standard um now it's entirely
nepotistic bullshit right or oh how do
you write on an essay oh we want
well-rounded students right all this
stuff is completely so the
admissions people can use whatever
subjective criteria they want right
there are no more
they want to do away with the last bit
of objective criteria in college
admissions
um
with regard to iq is a really bad
indicator of intelligence
uh all right
this was posted mainstream
uh science on race and intelligence
i don't agree with everything in this
document but
this was posted signed by
uh 52 university professors in 1994
and we won't talk about the race ones
but
um intelligence is a very general mental
capability uh it reflects a broader and
deeper capability for comprehending our
surroundings
intelligence so defined can be measured
and iq tests measure it well
intelligence tests measure well they are
among the most accurate
in technical terms reliable and valid of
all psychological tests and
assessment um well there are different
types of intelligence tests
they all measure the same intelligence
so like you say iq tests are bad tests
of
intelligence i mean you can define
intelligence to mean whatever you want
if you define intelligence to mean piano
playing skills and that's probably true
but iq is strongly related probably more
so than any other single measurable
human trait
to many important educational
occupational
uh economic and social outcomes whatever
iq tests measure it's a great practical
and social importance
um oh yeah well i mean this is in a way
this is one of the real
taboo truths in society right uh and i
don't know i mean
you guys know my opinion on on dealing
with uh with truth
don't you need a psychologist to conduct
the iq test
i think for the high end ones you do
what did tele say about iq
she was largely a pseudo-scientific
swindle
i mean the fact that telev wrote this is
it's interesting
i don't know maybe i'm really not
prepared to have this debate
can i tell you what i'm doing with your
uh
subscription fee um you're funding
uh chinese click forms
that promote my content on tick tock
uh because i work for the kardashians
all right read and review the article
this is the best measure in psychology
well let's let's let's contrast this
with
i mean did i get scammed right and i i'm
i'm
considering that i that i may have
gotten scammed with this stuff
um i generally
took this as mostly true um it may not
be
and i would i would certainly accept
that
um if it was true and this is i know
yeah you're not supposed to talk about
this stuff yeah cancel me whatever
whatever whatever
i mean okay so how do we find truth on
this
um i mean yeah i guess this is like it's
just it's a really
kind of biased topic right
iq correlates
i do not want a business insider article
maybe scientific american let's see what
wikipedia says
people who store hot who score high on
iq tests become
iq researchers
but it's not it's not a topic i i've
heard also about like fluidic
intelligence
and crystalline intelligence
and if you think about like iq measures
uh fluidic intelligence
yeah that's a sad truth too
fluid intelligence peaks at around age
20 i mean this is this has been
this has been a thing in my life like i
could remember
um getting better at things and not just
at specific tasks
but getting better at getting better at
things and this has stopped
and it's a sad i mean it's just a sad
thing in life
the validity of iq is pretty good at
least according to my professors
i mean it's possible right so you you if
you
view if you're communist you can't have
something like iq
right um because well you know
iq goes against equality right
um especially if it correlates with
let's scott alexander
i think in his he had a post about it
where he said basically it correlates
with
almost everything people would consider
a positive trait except
for uh likely to reproduce
well so okay i mean let's let's assume
that there is some test you can give and
here's here's really
you're right like let's think about what
i would actually want maybe i'm naive to
think that it's as simple as an iq test
all i know is that an iq test is a whole
lot more
fair than
a legacy than saying you can go here
because your father went here because
your grandfather went here or crap like
that
well the problem with a math test is
you're testing for whether somebody
learned math what you really want to
test for is somebody's capability to
learn
right um i mean one way to do this may
be to make a game
like if you make a game up where maybe
this is better
if you make a game up where there's this
movie the wizard
where the last scene people play uh
super mario 3 and
i mean the movie is just pretty much a
scam to introduce super mario 3.
sat does correlate sat iq correlation
see if we can find paper
uh you know what i realized that like
you can't have this conversation
like
yeah you know you shouldn't yeah i
honestly you know i shouldn't even
brought this stuff up right
because it's not
i mean maybe this is a big problem like
in society with this stuff in general
you develop stuff that's basically
proxies for iq tests because you don't
want to use iq tests directly
but i mean this is my theory about the
internet and overall internet decline
right as something becomes easier to use
like if you have the internet in a way
used to have
an intelligence barrier maybe not just
an intelligence barrier but a
like motivational barrier to get onto it
think about how you use your voice yeah
fuck off that shit
um no i hate those people i hate those
think about how you use your voice
people right
i will always speak truth now i'm not
going to repent for the truth
when they come and they put me in the
handcuffs
uh and they yeah you know what honestly
if if they like started torturing me
maybe i'd repent
but you know you'd have to physically
torture me
reddit's not anymore so what okay let's
think about something more constructive
right
google
uses this thing called navboost
and part of the problem with things that
look like this is like
there's no way to downvote right not
clicking on a link
is nowhere near as strong as a down vote
is saying like there's no way to say
this link is bad right um say for
example you do a google search where
there's there's two links
and
like link one
is good and exactly what you want but
link two is also pretty good
right versus the scenario where link one
is
terrible and link two is exactly what
you want right there's no way to
distinguish terrible
from also pretty good uh where like
there's no there's no inhibitory
connections like that now different
social media sites have done this kind
of differently right some of them have
upvotes and down
votes some of them only have upvotes
youtube comments have upvotes
and down votes where they don't show you
the number
uh don't let masses determine
what's um what's good or not
who determines that right
like is there like a hm
so you have curated blogs you you have
curated blogs guern's a curated blog
hmm
i mean this this is this is this is
interesting stuff too
um
one of the things that
some countries going to do this
right some country is going to start
intelligence amplification i don't know
how all this works
but if you could do the you know okay so
you you you give
let's assume iq is valid i'm not gonna
not gonna have that debate but um
whatever your proxy method is right or
you want wealth you want anything you
want to make you want to make rich kids
you want to make smart kids the same
same method works um take
tons of people's dna and then do
correlation analysis
figure out which genes are you know more
more likely to make intelligent which
genes are more likely to make you rich
and then do embryo selection on that
um you might even be able to do this
like recursively right you can maybe do
it every other generation
but the first country that does this
is going to in my opinion so clearly
dominate the world
no this isn't gattica right gattaca is
about taking the people who are already
born and saying you can or can't do this
based on
um intelligence tests or based on
genetic tests for
whatever proxies they want uh but this
is just it's
i mean it's it's a form of it's a form
of eugenics right
um again oh eugenics it gets a bad rap
yeah because you know
historically eugenics has been used to
force people to do things
this isn't forcing anybody
it's really interesting
oh see you gotta trust corn
studies of economics typically find that
one iq point corresponds to an increase
of wages on the order of one percent
other
things equal
see this is this is how everybody in the
world should talk
i wish i could talk more like this you
know we should all strive to
a whole list of citations
and i trust that like warren read it
correctly
all right all right let's let's go back
to teleps thing on iq
yeah this is the whole thing is
derailment unfortunately
but now i feel like you know
here's maybe uh a good rule of thumb
right
i heard a
uh
this was in a class on on relationships
at northwestern
where the professor said in order to
to have a successful relationship uh you
have to have sex five
times more than you fight for every one
fight
um you have to uh couples that do this
couples that show
this basic ratio do well i don't know
completely anecdotal but
i mean i almost think the same thing
with controversy and like you know real
real truthful right you you need to you
can't have just controversy
but if you have no if you if you're just
finding truth about esoteric things the
unobama refers this to this is like
surrogate activities right
like truths that are completely
irrelevant to
the modern world like oh well no
so algae is turned from blue to
yellow in the presence of dimethyl
sulfoxide like okay
i mean that might be true but it's
irrelevant you need to keep a good ratio
you need to keep a good ratio between
controversy and uh
and truth finding with a whole lot more
truth finding a whole lot more sex
than um i'll read some stuff on
interpretation of statistics
if an idea unless it's an unreasoned
ideological immune response my prior is
that it's true
no i mean i think one big example
against that is like holocaust denialism
right you have people who get very upset
about that
but like you know it doesn't mean it's
true right which is which is weird i
always find these denialism things
um climate change denialism there's a
big ideological immune response
uh to that like people oh how could they
say climate change isn't real
but like i don't know it seems real
at least like to an extent
i don't trust the atlantic i don't trust
any news websites on this
news is propaganda
um okay so let's let's let's analyze
this as as dispassionately as possible
um
iq is a stale test
so i'm not sure what that means right
like because it's old it's not good
i think generally we found on the stream
that the opposite is true
um
the concept is poorly thought out
mathematically by the field
see just just just just looking at these
two things
from a uh
like kind of naive perspective this one
has a lot of studies
this one it has a lot of links to to
external studies where you can verify
each statement whereas this whole
paragraph doesn't
right um and then this is this is uh
this is a logical fallacy
right um just because racists say the
sun is shining doesn't mean it's dark
outside right
um just because it's promoted by bad
people doesn't necessarily make it bad
see i like i don't this also it's like
it's promoted by psychometrics pedalers
looking for suckers
military boo large corporations boo
i don't know
i mean okay so this is this is a very
good point
if there's a good citation of this right
if the effect is
actually lower than the variance between
tests for the same individual
morality doesn't always relate to truth
i don't know i don't like i don't see
just just looking at these two things as
objectively as possible
and and ask the question i mean look at
this stuff
you know you're tagging racism and
alt-right
uh who gives these people a platform who
like who
whoever invoking the name
god you know i did it now and like this
is
i mean this is the real problem this is
the real problem with with
this whole peta approach to everything
these days
which is
you care about animal ethics okay let's
generate as much outrage as possible to
get our message out there
if someone shows me something that looks
like this something that
makes this point but stated like this
i'm much more inclined to believe that
um you know i find
larry summers was the uh was the
president of harvard
um
so he was fired for uh
well not exactly sure why he was fired
but
i i really liked what stephen pinker
said
um influential psychologist stephen
pinker defended legitimacy of summer's
january lecture
um when asked if summer's talk was
within the pale of legitimate academic
discourse he responded
good grief shouldn't everything be
within the pale of legitimate academic
discourse as long as it's presented with
some degree of rigor
this is the difference between the
university in the madrasa there is
certainly enough evidence for the
hypothesis to be taken seriously
um and you can read you can read the the
talk and make up your own opinion but
i i'll like
i've been thinking about this for a
while and i think probably the only
solution
to this whole problem here is building
new universities
is building new universities where the
point
of the university actually is the
pursuit of truth
because i'm not sure that's true for
2020 harvard
um yeah online iq tests are very they're
very much like online personality tests
you know
oh figure out which which jonas brother
are you the most like
pinker gets way too much shit for
stating the world's become a better
place over time
no doom we must promote doom and gloom
yeah yeah all right so how do we end up
here
um how do we end up here from
from trying to make a better search
engine
in a way maybe that's
no but this is okay this this problem is
this problem is easier to solve
the search engine problem is easier to
solve
what you really want to figure out is
for each website what was the intent of
its creation
right and even if you didn't
like explicitly rank based on that i
mean imagine
you you just
tagged everything with that right tag
everything with
going back to that like jessica thing
right
um
how do i find my passion yes so
like if this website just were tagged
with the call to action
all right like like like
i did the uh i did the tech crunch talk
i did the tech crunch comma talk
um one of the youtube comments
criticized me it said
uh this doesn't have a good call to
action
and i mean they were kind of right
from a marketing perspective what you
want to do i've gotten better about this
the medium post is you want to at the
basically at the bottom after someone's
bought in you know they've read all of
this here are the seven questions i ask
myself to discover my passion
um
this is the
like call to action right this is
the whole purpose of the post is to get
you to click that link
this is this is foreplay for the link
basically um if you just put the link
right up here
well no i mean some people might want to
sign up for the free 30-day life purpose
challenge right but like like like be
honest in your intentions
yeah i don't know
are we about to live through a decline
is there anything we can do about it
no it's not it's not climate change
all of these all of these
technical problems could be solved
relatively easily
uh there's a quote from um permutation
city
where let's see if i can find it
um
the quote was something along the lines
of see
again that's not
these aren't these aren't people trying
to
um promote any bullshit that's
legitimately just a hard search i'm sure
my things aren't perfect
though actually if i posted that on
reddit and somebody had the book i'm
sure they could find it so that's really
um what you want
but
the quote basically is that like the
environment is is is
already entirely man-made when people
are like oh we want to restore to a
pristine state of nature there is no
pristine state of nature
everything about our environment is
entirely controlled
so you know let's build the best one we
possibly can
you know
on a personal level about this stuff
the singularity is extremely scary and
it's been scary to me for a really long
time
i worry so much
if we're not a society that can
understand believe comprehend and
embrace basic truths
how are we going to deal with the
immense power that technology is about
to give to us
uh
look at what look at what we built the
internet man internet
beautiful thing ever the internet the
internet is the greatest the greatest
equalizer
uh in the history of mankind and
i increasingly feel like it's been
weaponized
it has been it has been weaponized for
not even
not even by a group of people and that's
why
conspiracy theories are so alluring to
so many people
the belief that there is an evil cabal
of lizard men
actually running anything everything is
actually more comforting than the truth
which is the lizard man lives within all
of us
so i don't know we may not have a long
time
um another thing that was brought up was
i'm not afraid of uh
self-improving recursively
self-improving ais
i'm not afraid of the machines going out
of control and doing not what they're
told
i'm afraid of the machines doing exactly
what they're told i'm just afraid of
what they're going to be told
the problem with nuclear bombs isn't
accidental explosions it's deliberate
explosions
and ai is going to be the same way
conspiracy theories are usually easier
to understand than the truth i mean
yeah there's a classic there's a classic
one about that too and it's like
um well so you know you could believe
that that you know the the lightning
storm is caused by
uh the positive and negative ions mixing
in the upper ionosphere
which generated the lightning bolt which
struck and killed your
your daughter and it was kind of a
random fluke of nature
or you can believe that the woman down
the street is a witch who summoned up an
evil lightning bolt to murder your
daughter
right that's oh that's a good theory man
burn the witch
who's gonna save the world
let's improve the internet first i mean
in some ways if we did improve the
internet
how much of our thought is now being
structured
by twitter and google and facebook how
much of the world's thought
is now being structured by these
vortexes
this isn't a joke anymore you know the
internet starts
it all starts out as oh hey it's all fun
and games it's
it's horrifying now in some ways did we
miss the singularity did it already
happen
are the machines already playing us or
are we just are we just
fodder the machines want the likes man
the machines are learning to improve the
likes
and um
you you make the like for the machine
are we all raging at the collective
obsolescence of humanity yo
how many computers died from coronavirus
none
okay i tried to read nick land i found i
found it difficult
um computers have this cool
computers don't learn the same way
humans do
um computers or this fourth paradigm of
learning if you think of the first
paradigm of learning is like
single-celled organisms
and single-celled organisms learn not to
go to the light by all the ones going to
the light dying whatever genetic code
makes them go to the light uh dies out
slowly and then you know they all go
away from the light
right uh first paranoid of learning the
second paradigm of learning is like how
rats learn right you can take a cage in
a
you know put around a cage and electrify
one of the grid cells and the rat
touches it the rats like oh yeah that
hurt
um and the rat won't uh the rat will go
away
and not touch it anymore and they might
even be able to communicate this to the
fellow rats in the cage but they're
definitely not going to leave a rat
encyclopedia about how you shouldn't go
to that
tile on the third paradigm of learning
is human it's cultural
right we learn god we all thought there
was deep things in 2000 years of chess
culture until
until alpha zero came around and uh
relearned all of chess and rediscovered
all of chess theory in 24 hours
um but yeah humans learn culturally and
pass things down through generations and
you stand on the shoulder of giants
that's a good quote
uh and then there's this fourth paradigm
of learning and the fourth paradigm of
learning
is i know kung fu the fourth pound i'm
learning is plugging a wire into the
back of your head and instead of having
to go through 10 years of training sure
you can learn it through books but the
learning itself is still
hard you just put the thing in and say i
know kung fu
and that's how computers learn
um
you have a hard time relating to my
concerns well
because of maslov's hierarchy of needs
right
uh there's no more points of view when
your only thought is food
the bible has replaced been replaced
with a survival guide
that uses perishables instead of
parables because there's no stories left
to preach
there's no life lessons left to teach
anyone why bother
who are we this is from the nofx song
you know i could i could play the song
but
uh then i'll get copyright striked who
are we are we the intellects or the
insects
we're not the ones who will ever know
the answer it's impossible for us to
imagine what's right in front of us and
i guess that's what makes us human
but being human only lets us see a
little further than the animals
oh right like you say yeah okay whatever
your whatever your needs are
now like look i do i care
do i care if if the world's on board
with fighting the singularity what does
fighting the singularity even mean
right do we do we not the unibomber do
we mail bombs the compsci professors
kidding bro like that's a joke like like
why you do that
you know it's it's a dumb i don't know
like like and i understand the feeling
of
of powerlessness but
ban computers now ban computers now you
can't go back
technology doesn't work that way name a
technology that's successfully been
banned
how is nuclear proliferation
well yeah but i don't think
i i wonder if the right metric here is
not
number of nuclear missiles right if one
person has
ten thousand nuclear missiles that's not
so different i would much rather
one person have ten thousand nuclear
missiles than a hundred people each have
one
that's a doomsday clock
all right i think we'll leave you guys i
think i have i have a little
presentation
um that i gave
we could do this presentation
um
guys i don't know how to fix a voice i
don't know how to fix it you know
um disclaimer
all right
uh so yeah you have uh synapses and
neurons
uh so when you look at this is the new
tesla chip
um they have multiply accumulates uh
multiplies look like synapses
and accumulate to look like neurons
right so you have uh different
well i think i have yeah the synapse is
a multiplier with a learned weight and
the neuron is an accumulator
um so max approximately correspond
to the number of synapses right not to
the number of neurons
uh because the neuron is all of the the
accumulation done
uh so bioflops is synapses times clock
rate right
so that's the metric we're going to use
um so here's uh
your boy c elegans um c elegans is about
the same as an altair 8800
uh so this is the smallest uh organism
with
a nervous system um
as i said and right how many neurons it
has it has like 200 neurons and that's
maybe
what you could simulate in an altair um
we have an ant uh and it's about two
gigaflops
of compute power you know a surprising
amount big leap from c elegans to ants
and that's about a raspberry pi
an old raspberry pi the new ones have a
bit more but so you know
raspberry pi and about the same that's
about 20 000 c elegans
uh so here's a b uh b is about 500 amps
they're way smarter than ants look at
them you can just tell right
that thing looks dumb man looks dumb
that looks a lot smarter you know it
grew all those little fuzzies it has all
those little intricate feelers
um b has about uh
200 gigaflops compute which is about the
same as a
uh common two um
and it's about 500 ants i'll say you get
to a mouse
uh if you guys have ever i mean i'm sure
you know you've interacted with bees
and auntie you crush an ant you know
okay yeah yeah okay it's an ant
um a b well they're a little more
skeptical of bees you know you can tell
every you kind of know intuitively that
bees are a bit of chappy versus virgin
ant
um a mouse
uh 100 teraflops
so about the same as a bunch of uh as a
bunch of g-forces and
i had when i lived in palo alto i had
two pet mice princess and misty
uh and yeah i taught them to i taught
them to run mazes
and they're very they're very smart and
you can you can tell they're clever you
just look at them and you're like wow
um so that's 100 teraflops gets you yes
a cat is about two petaflops
uh maybe one rack um
i don't think i have it in here but for
reference dogs are actually they're
about
twice the neurons of of cats so you know
dog dog owners
a cat's about 20 mice uh that seems
about seems about right
um humans are 20 peter flops or about 10
cats
you you know whenever a cat lady has
more than 10 cats
the total number of cat flops in her
apartment
exceeds her number of flops um how is
this measured it's synapses times clock
rate
right bioflops um you can look
wikipedia's got a good uh
got a good article for this
um
this tells you uh so this is neurons
but synapses is just it's your fan out
factor on neurons
so you can go through all the animals
and it's a rough ranking of
um you know then you get uh humans and
then
god tier elephants
so human about 20 cats and is about one
rack of google tpu v3s
uh bioflopsy now this time clock right
so here's basically a summarization
um putting it in uh in log scale
um now it's wrong to talk about
um you can't do much with twenty page
flaps uh humanity is
a network uh so this is the the world
population there's you know real
singularity looking looking stuff right
there is no singularity and exponential
looks
the same every point you zoom to
um cats are not networked
uh cats are solo animals dogs are on
lands but only humans are networked like
the internet
um this is years and population
the rise of humanity was due to our
collective intelligence
i see no reason why we should assume the
brain software is particularly
good given its hardware
compute is a good proxy for intelligence
broadly
if you believe these three things oh
yeah software and hardware proceed
similar rates i saw i saw
more concrete breakdown of this recently
there's just an open ai paper that
talked about this
number of bio flops in the world
well 7.8 billion people
uh this is just a rough like the cats
and the mice don't really count for much
so the total number of flops
in humanity is like 10 to the 26th
so we got like 10 to the 26 total flies
how many total silicon flops are there
in the world
a hundred billion pedo flops or a
hundred trillion teraflops so for
reference your phone is
approximately a teraflop they're more
now
but clearly you know let's say there's
10 billion phones in the world 100
trillion is uh
10 000 times bigger so there's a lot
more biological compute in the world
than silicon compute it's total computer
civilization
number of silicon flux in the world
about 10 to the 21 so we're off by a
factor of about 10 to the 5.
here's the trend over time
at some point before this happens
assuming current
growth rates of computers
stay the same which they may not as
computers become more economically
productive we may put
more and more of our resources uh into
building computers
but either way
oh yeah the human population
when the green line goes above the blue
line
we are no longer the dominant species on
the planet
so how long do we have well
30 years 40 years
uh the end of humanity has already been
very clearly predicted
not the end right we're just no longer
the horses didn't there are still horses
there's a few horses
you know we let children ride them at
the zoos and say
come ride the human witness the
antiquated human as it struggles to use
a keyboard
um
i hope we're getting pets i mean there's
a lot worse fates than pets
think of all the poor cows and chickens
in the world
um
oh no we definitely don't uh war
at least like old school style you know
give a lot of young men guns and tell
them to march in that vague direction
war
happens when your population uh
pyramids look like this right this is
why you get
uh local wars in africa because you have
such a top-heavy uh
population the we'll do that quick aside
u.s population versus like
nigeria population versus japan
i mean here's u.s versus nigeria right
um the united states one is rather
phallic
uh and people believe social security's
gonna work
well i i mean so this idea that like
like we're going to enter a new world
war is from my pers like looking at this
unlikely right who's going to fight this
war we're going to send the boomers
like i don't know about that um is it
going to be some weird
proxy cyber cold war thing that's been
going on for the last 50 years sure
um
the computers are reproducing a ton
faster than we are
in 2055 we're no longer the dominant
species on the planet
um total compute ever
so about a trillion alpha zeros that's
this is this is open ai's metric
uh pay to flop second days
um and then if you're a pure culturalist
if you believe humanity is actually its
culture when have computers
done more flops than the total of
humanity
it's 10 years later right so if you
really want to make a culturalist
hypothesis so yeah 1990
all the compute in the world was one
human oh guys it's so
cute look what it can do oh it can
almost do human thingies
2012 supercomputer crossed one human oh
man it beat us at chess
oh but it is only it is only one one one
human there's only like 500
supercomputers that's only 500 human
we've we we've taken out smaller towns
in that in
in nam and another one was fine man you
know
um yeah so here we are in 2020
and a silicon human costs about 1
million dollars
and there's about 100 000 silicon humans
right
so what's that the population of oh yeah
2038 you know i like that date for the
singularity
um pc crosses one human uh 2055
silicon flops more than bio silicon
compute more than bio compute
is this the singularity well my
definition is when humans are capable
well computers are capable of doing
everything humans can do at least as
well
moore's law's law of human economics we
know this stuff
um the top computer is 200 petaflops
it's about 10 humans
it's well under the number meaning teams
of humans who can effectively
collaborate
right can computers effectively
collaborate well computers can't really
collaborate in inflexible
uh ways we haven't seen computers
capable of collaborating in flexible
ways the way humans can
so teams of humans are now the dominant
driver of moore's law
but once computers are 100x faster
it kind of stands to reason that we can
put a thousand humans of compute in one
box
humans may no longer be the high-end
driver of things
meaning this is going to accelerate even
faster singularities in 2038
uh yeah you can read those if you want
to be be
make some make some arguments against
this basic hypothesis but really look
i got 18 years you know what can i do
google facebook
who are you what are you doing
what are you doing oh yeah man how many
ad dollars you made next quarter yeah
that's really gonna matter bro
that's really gonna matter all right the
apocalypse is nigh
2038 uh
maybe next stream so like every good
apocalypse salesman
you know i i i bring you in i tell you
what the solution is the solution is
going to be to sign up for my college
and we'll fight the singularity together
um
yeah uh nothing matters human extinction
is inevitable no
guys you can choose today to fight the
power i don't know if that's true or not
but it's sure better than like being a
doomer man
you know who likes doomers
um and
think the most important thing to
realize
in your life you can disagree with this
but if you are fundamentally in a
religious manner denying truth
right like your heaven's gateman
what if the rest of the world is a death
cult what if we live in a death cult
what if mainstream society is a death
cult
what do you do what if you build a cult
where the cult pursues honest rational
truth it would look like a cult today
and that's scary
um all right i gotta eat food thank you
all for watching the stream
um
you know what else can i do
what else can i do can i build a search
engine to fight against google
maybe is that the best way
fix the nsav cheerleader save the world
fix the internet save the world
plausible
don't be evil
build a new world yeah bro give me a
death note and i will
make i will purify the world uh if you
guys haven't watched that's my death
that's incredible
um could you save the world with a death
note probably not
the terror i don't know it's great the
anime explores it all
pretty well
um the way google is built do you need
to build something more evil than google
to beat it
maybe
time for career advice
yo
wake up um
i don't know how many people in how many
people in chat like
believe in a fairly imminent singularity
i'm seeing like 50 50. uh
to those that do believe have you truly
internalized that belief
do you think about it every day this is
your future this is your real future
global warming is an easy problem to
solve with like compared to this
right um humanity didn't grow
big brains because we needed to solve
natural problems we grew big brains kind
of for politics
right this one was
something i said i was home with my
family it's like what have i done with
the last six years of my life i've done
politics
what is what is founding a company maybe
that's why i hate it so much
um but
no it's applied politics right
we didn't grow big brains i don't know
man except for them elephants we sure
did
um yeah but if we get off fossil fuels
and we switch everything to electric
the singularity is still coming in 2038
well no i mean what is what is running a
company right running a company is
political
like right you're dealing with you're
dealing with
uh how to balance the needs and wants of
many people versus the needs and the
wants of
a clientele of investors
um
it's money in power uh
i don't know can we all join a pact and
be like
bro i really don't want money in power i
just want some semblance of uh
hope for the future i hope i mean that's
the wrong way to think about it i want
to
um i was at a i was at a dinner with
some uh
maybe maybe i don't think they'd be
upset if i'd characterize them as like
right wingish type of people
and one thing that like saddened me
about it
um is i didn't hear
like a positive vision for the future
i i certainly don't hear one from from
um
you know like communists right
um who has one
is that what we need
eat the rich steal their shit man
lifestyles in the rich and famous yeah
man
all right all right you're a cow you're
a cow right before the rise of humanity
man
and and you're sitting there and you're
like eat the rich cows
the spotted white cows you know
oh yeah you know whatever whatever
bullshit cow politics you're all doing
and now
look at the cows today you ever seen a a
cow factory farm you know
look at the cows today man
yeah yeah you know
these cows used to be fighting over oh
well i want this pasture i want this
pasture
and now they're all in cages like humans
in the matrix
the brown cows stole our jar this is the
stupidity
man why are we about to get banned
because i spread the truth about cows
um i mean i'm just saying no
like to be very concrete and factual if
you're
a cat before the rise of humanity
right what do you do
you know this this new dominant species
is coming and you're tasty
you know you going vegan is you being
polite to the cows it's not a very good
but the cow should promote veganism
should we should we get together and
promote a system of ethics where the
machines don't enslave us
um lose the will to live we'll we'll
fight back well
i do have hope i do have hope for the
2020s
um
concretely one thing i have hoped for
and
i mean we try this a bit with comma ai
it was my best idea at the time
is decentralization the more
we can decentralize ai and power
uh the better off i think we're all
going to be
right um so
we see we see a lot of you know i think
i think
a lot of people would agree that
problems come
from these from these centralizations of
power and
even the centralizations of power
themselves may agree with that
all right like even the
um
i think i think mark zuckerberg went
before congress and said look please
regulate us right
you want me to regulate speech on the
platform you know tell me how to do it
i'll do it right
uh like once there is somebody to
to to to blame it's um
you know it becomes almost their
responsibility
so decentralized stuff doesn't really
seem to have
this problem or put it this way
it is much easier for people to accept
dying from cancer than dying from murder
because you can kind of accept death
from cancer
stoically maybe not so much anymore if
you believe in a treatment but at least
historically when people would get
cancer it's like
you know what it's it's uh it's my time
and god chose this for me it's a much
easier thing to accept
than um well
being murdered
genuine decentralization doesn't seem
reliable is this a technical problem
could certainly build a reliable
decentralized twitter wouldn't have been
hacked like
central estuary
centralization's not necessarily part of
the capitalist game
um maybe in a world where
money has influence in politics it does
but i don't think capitalism in general
is pro
centralization or decentralization uh
historically
the way that you make money is um
you know you build something for
everybody right you build something that
you're going to sell to millions of
people i guess this is still kind of
true
am i vegan no
um i mean am i gonna
am i gonna save the cows if i if i
became a vegan
no uh i will become a vegan
once there is artificial
hamburgers that taste identical with
cows
we have decentralized social media yeah
but
it's not as good right and i think
how about this and we could talk about
drug addiction under the same lens of
social media addiction
right if if somebody made
better heroin and better heroin
was made you feel the same way heroin
does
but it doesn't um
you know it's not addictive let's say
all right like it's a simple change we
could make to heroin
we could take heroin and we could make
non-addictive hair right and how you
actually do that let's assume it's
something like hyper complex i can
reverse the
uh i can like re-encode the memory to
not
re-trigger the pleasure when you think
about it um
i think most addicts would switch from
heroin to better heroin
of course they would who wants to be
addicted to something nobody um they
want the feeling but they don't want to
be addicted right so like
what is the the the better heroine of of
twitter
right uh what is the better heroine of
cow
so that's um
lab grown cow
non-addictive heroin all the health
benefits of addictive era
uh no linky presentation you guys saw it
here once
great adhd streams now it was pretty
adhd
um yeah i don't know that is what
organizing the world
like why do you want to do it right do i
want like a better search engine so i
can get the real truth about iceland
uh coronavirus results no i want a
better search engine so
people can find uh real truth
and not propaganda
all right thank you all for watching
great to have you all here we can uh
fight the future together
maybe i hope bye